Register of the Italian subject collection, 1915-1996
Hoover Institution Archives
Italian subject collection,
1915-1996
XX748
7 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 3 videotape cassettes, 1 phonotape (3.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Leaflets, pamphlets, campaign literature, propaganda, and other printed matter, relating to various aspects of twentieth-century Italian history and politics, and especially to Italian elections of 1976 and after.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives. An increment was added in 2011.
Accruals
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Scope and Content of Collection
Leaflets, pamphlets, election campaign literature, propaganda, and other printed matter, relating to various aspects of twentieth-century Italian history and politics, and especially to Italian elections of 1976 and after.
Access Points
Elections--Italy.; Italy.; Italy--History--20th century.; Italy--Politics and government--20th century.; Video tapes.; Phonotapes.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1915-1994. (Box 1-7)
  Leaflets, pamphlets, campaign literature, propaganda, and other printed matter, relating to various aspects of twentieth-century Italian history and politics, and especially to the Italian elections of 1976 and after.
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1994. (Cassette cabinet, Videotape cabinet)
  Forza Italia political party: phonotape cassette of party songs and three videotapes, including national party convention, "La sfida di Forza Italia" and "Spot Referendum".
CONTAINER LIST
- SUBJECT FILE, 1915-1994
  SEE CARD CATALOG FOR INCREMENTS THAT MAY HAVE BEEN RECEIVED AFTER DEC 1994
  - History
    - Miscellany. Cartoons, serial issues, pamphlets, leaflets, reports, press releases, underground literature, bulletins, and clippings, 1915-1948, relating to the monarchy and the rise of fascism, Italian participation in the two world wars, Italian resistance during World War II, and to political, social, and economic conditions in Italy. In Italian and English (Box 1)
    - 1915-1922
      - Fiume Question. See 1922-1943, Fiume Question
      - Propaganda. Flyers, 1917-1918, directed to Czechs, Poles, Hungarians, Romanians, and Croats with the Austro-Hungarian Army during World War I
    - 1922-1943
      - General. Leaflets and proclamations, 1921-1943. In Italian
      - Fiume Question. Proclamations, newspaper issues, and correspondence, 1918-1924, relating to the occupation of Fiume by Italian nationalists and to the growth of the fascist movement. In Italian (Box 4)
      - Italo-Ethiopian War. Leaflets, 1935-1936, distributed by the Italian Government in Great Britain, relating to the Italo-Ethiopian War (Box 1)
    - 1945-
      - Elections (Box 2-3)
        - 1976. Pamphlets, newspapers, party programs, and other printed election materials concerning the elections of June 20-21. In Italian
        - 1987. Pamphlets, flyers, leaflets, stickers, and postcards issued by the Socialist Party for the general elections of June 14. In Italian (Box 4)
        - 1989. Leaflets, brochures, postcards, and newspapers issued by various parties for the local elections in Rome of October 29-30
        - 1992. Party programs, brochures, newspaper issues, flyers, leaflets, and stickers issued by various parties for the general elections of April 5 and 6. In Italian (Box 5-6)
        - 1994. Party programs, brochures, newspaper issues, flyers, leaflets, and stickers issued by various parties for the general elections of 1994 (Box 7)
  - Political parties. Broadsides, leaflets, and election campaign material, 1950-1961, consisting of electoral and other propaganda issued by various political parties. In Italian (Box 1)
  - Miscellany. International bulletin, published by the European Labor Committees/Milan, June 1975, relating to the World Bank. In Italian (Box 5)
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1994
  - Phonotape cassette of party songs, Forza Italia Party (Cassette-cabinet Cassette cabinet)
  - 3 videotape cassettes of Forza Italia Party, includes party congress, "La sfida di Forza Italia" and "Spot Referendum" (Videotape-cabinet Videotape cabinet)
- Incremental Materials (Box 8)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described. Contact us at hooverarchivesinfo@stanford.edu